MD.SAHIDUR RAHAMAN

Mobile: 09732234209

Email: sahibiet@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

To work in challenging environment & execute my responsibilities with honesty, sincerity& dedication. To work in team orientation & utilizing my existing skills & at the same time give me an opportunity to learn new ones, always ready to work in any environment.

CARRIER PROFILE

A mechanical engineer with 5 years professional. 3.5 years experience in sheet metal dies of manufacturing processes and production sequence of automobile sector. I do involve in every step of manufacturing process. Designing & Manufacturing knowledge of Press Tools, Mold and Jig &Fixture.1.3 years experience in heat treatment shop of foundry departmental roll industry.

CURRENTS ASSIGNMENTS

Presently working with : Gontermann peipers india ltd (kolkata).

Period of consortium : March 2014 to till now.

Designation : Junior Manager C T C : 2.65 Lac per annum

CURRENTS RESPONSIBILITIES

- Submit the **Daily Work Management Report (DWM)** and monitoring.
- Planning day to day activities, production schedules for achieving daily production.
- Responsible for continuous improvement on shop floor by establishing **TPM**, & 5'S activities.
- Provide the training to operators like a **5s,Tpm** etc.
- Co-ordinate with workers & ensure proper housekeeping.
- Attend daily pre-shift meetings and carry out assigned workloads as per Production.
- Analyzing the drawing of incoming materials.
- Daily SAP entry.
- Assign work load to operators & achieving daily production target.
- Proper utilization of Manpower.
- Shop floor administration, handling skilled manpower.

PAST WORK EXPERIENCES

Company : Eastern Equipment Enterprises, Kolkata

Designation : Production Engineer (Tool Room)

Duration : June 2013 to March 2014.

Client : Tata Steel, Non-Conventional Engineering (BHEL),

Railways (CLW, DLW), Naively, IFFCO, VSP, BEMLetc,

RESPONSIBILITIES

• Preparing production process and planning.

- Responsible for reaching production targets in workshop.
- Handling of all shop floor activities such as cutting, bending, welding, assembly etc.
- Preparing Drawings for shop floor.
- Day to day production planning and achieve maximum Production.
- Technical problems Solving and Trouble Shooting.

•

Company : **Tata Motors Ltd., Jamshedpur**

Designation : Tool & Die Maker (CTR)

Duration : April 2009 – Oct 2010.

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Attend daily pre-shift meetings and carry out assigned workloads as per Production.
- Manufacturing & Assembly of various Sheet metals Dies.
- Final Die Inspection, rectification, Die try out, Press working.
- Technical problems Solving and Trouble Shooting.
- Co-ordinate with workers & ensure proper housekeeping.
- To prepare management information reports for progress in the department

Company : Force Motors Ltd., Pune.

Designation : Trainee (Tool Room)

Duration : Sept. 2007 – Oct 2008

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Manufacturing & Assembly of various Sheet metals Dies.
- Supervising Tool room activities as per plan
- Final Die Inspection, rectification, Die try out, Press working.
- Technical problems Solving and Trouble Shooting.
- Co-ordinate with workers & ensure proper housekeeping.

STRENGTH & SKILLS

- Proven knowledge in Press tool and injection mould Manufacturing.
- Knowledge of **MS Office**.
- Designing in Auto Cad.
- Knowledge of SAP, IBM LOTUS.

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY in **MECHANICAL ENGINEERING**, First Class with 8.14 CGPA Year of pass out was 2013 from West Bengal University of Technology, Kolkata

(West -Bengal).

And

DIPLOMA IN TOOL AND DIE MAKING, First Class with 68.72% marks,

Year of pass out was 2008 from Central Tool Room and Training Centre, Kolkata (West Bengal).

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

SECONDARY EXAMINATION, Second Class With 57.62% marks,

Year of pass out 2004 from West Bengal Board of Secondary Examination, Kolkata (West Bengal)

LANGUAGES KNOWN

: Hindi / Bengali / English

PRESENT ADDRESS

: C/O-Basudeb Mondal

Po+Vill-Joka Mondal Para, P.s-Thakurpukur Opposite Joka Post Office, Kol-700104

PERSONAL DEATILS

Date of Birth : April 30, 1989

Gender : Male
Marital Status : Married
Nationality : Indian

Permanent Address : S/o – Md. Shajamal Mollah

Seharapara(W), Ward No-10

P.O. & P.S.-Suri, Dist.-Birbhum, Pin-731101(W.B.)

DECLARATION:

I hereby declare that all the above maintain information is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Reference may be provided if required.	
Place	Signature
Date	(md.sahidur rahaman)